

As a Software Engineer and Full Stack Web Developer, I am experienced in contributing to team success through the art of software development and dedication to my craft. Rooted in a passion for learning, I have built a strong skill set which includes 5+ years' experience in applying Object-Oriented and Functional programming techniques.

**2** (734)969–5442

in/in/luke-belinc

★/luke-belinc

♠ luke@belinc.dev

# **Experience**

# **Software Engineer**

**Associate** > Built and maintained internal software tools for the Experience Management **Product Support organization** 

- Verint Systems > Automated workflows to create efficiency of scale while also reducing manual
- 02/2022–08/2022 > Periors Delivered continuous QoL updates to legacy software and systems
  - ➤ Built and deployed single page web applications via AWS EC2
  - > Tasked with providing all necessary CLI training to colleagues
  - > Coordinated multiple projects from initial planning through deployment
  - > Acted as admin for 20+ mission critical PowerBI waterfall reports and data
  - > Utilized Agile software development approach with each project
  - > Doubled 2022 annual release target goal by August

- **Systems** > Built software extensions for the GEOS-Chem and WRF-Chem modeling systems
- **Programmer** > Drew up comprehensive bug reports to identify pain points and provided solutions
- WSU-Huang Lab
  03/2020-10/2020

  Authored scripts to interpret and generate maps from atmospheric data models
  Automated software execution and data collection using Bash, cron, and Slurm via WSU's HPC
  - > Implemented GNU Make to automate software builds
  - > Held regular CLI training sessions with research students

# Skill Set

**Languages** C, C++, C#, Java, Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, Go, Bash, Haskell, CommonLisp, FORTRAN, Ruby

**Frameworks/Libraries** Angular, React, Express, Jasmine, POSIX, pandas, Tkinter, NumPy, NLTK, Qt, .NET, ASP.NET, ¡Query, Rails

**Tools** Unix shells (zsh, sh, Bash), GNU coreutils, Vim, Slurm, cron, PowerShell, Git, Node.js, Lagrange, Vim, Slurm, Cron, Cr AWS (S3, EC2, Lambda), Database Managament Systems (PostgreSQL, MySQL, Oracle Database), Jira, Confluence

**Methodologies** Agile, CI/CD, Behavior - and Test-driven development

# Projects/Hackathons

**Advent of Code** Various code challanges completed using Haskell, C++, and Python

**DHack** Designed health monitoring app using AWS Lambda, JavaScript and React Native. Won 2nd place overall and 1st place for the FitBit challenge.

**MHacks 8** Designed set of dev tools for remote maintainance of GM Console software. Used C, JavaScript, and Wayland to manipulate system and interact with screen remotely.

Chinese Character Dictionary Designed a simple character meaning and stroke order dictionary and thesaurus using Python, PostgreSQL, and Qt

**Mock Terminal** POSIX shell built in C

# Education

### **Wayne State University** B.S. in Computer Science Detroit, MI 2016-2021

# References

**Matt Crawford** Director, Product Support **2** (248) 595–5635 in/in/th3mattcrawford

**Matthew Heinrich** Engineer, DevOps **2** (646) 385-5524

in/in/matthew-heinrich-11b31216a